Guide to the Stanford University, Graduate School of Business, records
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives.
Stanford University, Graduate School of Business, records
1931-2015
SC1266
Stanford University. Graduate School of Business. Public Management Program.
Stanford University. Graduate School of Business
92.5 Linear feet
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was transferred to Stanford University, Special Collections in June 2015.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
The Stanford Graduate School of Business was formed in 1925, in order to establish a West Coast alternative to the business schools of the East Coast.
Scope and Contents
The collection is 92.5 linear feet, and consists of documents and publications produced by the Graduate School of Business (GSB), for internal and external audiences, such as: program publicity materials, orientation materials, newsletters, student newspapers, annual reports, and yearbooks. Also included are curriculum program planning documents such as course and seminar files, and faculty manuals and reports. Files related to specialized GSB programs such as the Public Management Program (PMP), the Executive Education program, and the Global Management Program (GMP) Study Trips are also included. Also found are documents related to GSB space planning, and the planning and construction of the Knight Management Center.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Graduate School of Business. Curricula.; Stanford University. Graduate School of Business. History.; Stanford University. Graduate School of Business. News and Publications.; Stanford University. Graduate School of Education. Buildings.; Universities and colleges--Business management
Collection Contents
- Videotapes: orientation, women’s conference, gender & grades, commencement 1984 (Box 1)
- Student meeting agendas and minutes, 2006-2009 (Box 2)
- MBA orientation books, 2004-2006 (Box 3)
- MBA orientation books, 2007-2011 (Box 4)
- Orientation packets 1998-2009; videos: student shows, memorials, history of women in the GSB (Box 5)
- The Reporter (GSB student newspaper), 1969-1976 (Box 6)
- The Reporter (GSB student newspaper), 1976-1985 (Box 7)
- The Reporter (GSB student newspaper), 1994-1995; William Sproule clippings; School of Mortgage Banking course outlines, 1959-1961; mortgage banking seminars; Mortgage Bankers of America (MBA) material (Box 8)
- School of Mortgage Banking, 1962; Alumni Weekend archives; Dividends, 1997-1999; Graduate School of Credit and Financial Management, Notes on Course Development of Executive Abilities for Stanford and Dartmouth School (Box 9)
- Faculty seminars; faculty manuals (Box 10)
- J. Hugh Jackson letters; miscellaneous GSB pubs; Sloan program annual report, no. 6., no.8; Public Management Program Forum, 1989- (Box 11)
- GSB MBA program literature; news releases, 1980-1993 (Box 12)
- Public Management Program history (1 of 4) (Box 13)
- Public Management Program history (2 of 4) (Box 14)
- Public Management Program history (3 of 4) (Box 15)
- Public Management Program history (4 of 4) (Box 20)
- Miscellaneous publications: Delta Sigma Pi, 1948-1964; Spreadsheet, 1985-1995; Advisory Council (Box 16)
- Questionnaire Analysis, 1984; Center for Entrepreneurial Studies formulation study, 1999; Prospectus (MBA yearbook), 1954-1980 [incomplete] (Box 17)
- Prospectus (MBA yearbook) [incomplete run], 1982-2015 (Box 18)
- Stanford Executive Program yearbooks, 1960-1976 [incomplete]; Sloan 1973 - 40 Years of Memories (Box 19)
- Center for Entrepreneurial Studies (CES) materials (Box 21)
- GSB Executive Program (Box 22)
- Stanford Business School Magazine, 1993-1994; Alumni Bulletin (bound), 1931-1962 (Box 23)
- Alumni Bulletin (bound), 1962-1978 (Box 24)
- Executive Education publications, 1984-1988 (Box 39)
- Executive Education publications, 1989-1996 (Box 33)
- Executive Education publications, 1996-2003 (Box 25)
- New curriculum files (1 of 3) (Box 26)
- New curriculum files (2 of 3) (Box 27)
- New curriculum files (3 of 3) (Box 28)
- New curriculum binders, circa 2007 (Box 29)
- Construction photographs and planning discs (Box 30)
- GSB space planning (Box 31)
- Knight Management Center space planning; GSB miscellaneous publications, 1976-1985 (Box 32)
- GSB Program publications, 1967-1979 (Box 34)
- Global Management Program (GMP) history; GMP Study Trips, inception to 1996 (Box 35)
- GMP Study Trips, inception to 1999 (Box 36)
- GMP Study Trips, 1999-2004 (Box 37)
- GMP Study Trips, 2004-2008; Global Management Immersion Experience (GMIX) Reports, 1997-2002 (Box 38)
- Global Management Immersion Experience (GMIX) Reports, 2003-2004 (Box 40)
- Global Management Immersion Experience (GMIX) Reports, 2004-2005 (Box 41)
- Global Management Immersion Experience (GMIX) Reports, 2006-2009 (Box 42)
- Global Management Program miscellaneous: Stanford And IIMB - Indian Institute of Management Bangalore - Link (SAIL) program, Tsinghua program. Endeavor Program in Lane and Jackson libraries. (Box 43)
- GSB Miscellaneous Publications, 1958-2009 (Box 44)
- GSB in Singapore, 1983-2005 (Box 45)
- Student Life Office Orientation Files (Box 46)
- Student Life Office Orientation Files; Student Conferences (Box 47)
- Student Life Office Orientation Files; Student Conferences (Box 48)
- GSB Library: Statistics and Miscellaneous (Box 49)
- GSB Library: Statistics and Miscellaneous; GSB Library Selected Additions, 1958-1972 (Box 50)
- GSB Library Selected Additions, 1972-1986 (Box 51)
- GSB Library Selected Additions; 1986-1992; Miscellaneous MBA Program Publications (handbooks, promotional material, etc.), 1960s-2000s (Box 52)
- Miscellaneous MBA Program Publications (handbooks, promotional material, etc.), 1960s-2000s (Box 53)
- Center for Entrepreneurial Studies (CES) Videotapes (Box 54)
- Center for Entrepreneurial Studies (CES) Videotapes (Box 55)
- GSB Admission & Events, 1999-2007 (Box 56)
- GSB Library - Miscellaneous policy and procedure manuals, floorplans (Box 57)
- Jackson Library/Rosenberg Research Center Miscellaneous (Box 58)
- Jackson Library/Rosenberg Research Center Miscellaneous (Box 59)
- Oversize GSB Misc Publications, 1976-85; Knight Management Center Space planning (Box 60)
- The Reporter (GSB student newspaper), 1986-1989 (Box 61)
- The Reporter (GSB student newspaper), 1989-1994 (Box 62)
- The Reporter (GSB student newspaper), 1995-1998 (Box 63)
- The Reporter (GSB student newspaper), 1998-2001 (Box 64)
- The Reporter (GSB student newspaper), 2001-2010 (Box 65)
- GSB Singapore Program class photographs (Box 66)